

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/iqbalsinghsandhu/

igbal sandhu@icloud.com • 201.214.8101 • 1 Cider Mill Court, Montvale, NJ 07652

Profile

Iqbal is a data driven individual that loves to share stories and travel. A self starter who seeks out opportunities to collaborate and brainstorm, Iqbal is a proven influencer with years of experience at Apple. An eye for detail has manifested in a drive for action and a relentless work ethic. Iqbal strives to create the best in himself and others.

Areas of Expertise

Python, Pandas, Matplotlib Excel VBA HTML, CSS, Javascript Team Leadership

Excel VBA SQL/MongoDB Web Scraping Training Facilitation

Projects

- PySchools written in Python and Pandas. Analysis of school scores https://github.com/smartsingh/pyschools
- Sakila Queries to analyze sales data in SQL https://github.com/smartsingh/sakila_sql
- SurfsUp Flask and SQLAlchemy combine for climate analysis https://github.com/smartsingh/surfsup

Career Experience

Pro, Apple Inc; — May 2017 - Current, Northern New Jersey

- Built dashboards and visualizations using Python and Excel VBA to identify individuals who completed transactions with ApplyPay. Communicated insights and successes with team, leading to a 400% increase in ApplePay usage.
- Designed and maintained SQL databases for reporting results. Utilized these databases to build teams and communicate results, creating a store-wide focus on personal results and the customer experience.
- Analyzed and studied competitor products and services to educate and present findings to store teams. Highlighted industry trends and technologies to stimulate more robust conversations with customers.

Support Lead, Apple Inc; — November 2015 - May 2017, Wayne, NJ

- Aggregated sales data from SAP to measure accessory sales performance and create visualizations. Performed regression analysis in Excel and shared insights with leadership to craft sales and inventory strategies.
- Ran daily huddles to prepare store team for daily operations and focus teams on priorities. Inspired them to create world class customer experiences, resulting in customer satisfaction scores of between 70-80 during peak times.
- Empowered employees to take control of customer situations and repair relationships. Addressed customer concerns in person, through email, and via phone calls to ensure standards of service were met.

In Store Trainer, Apple Inc; — January 2015 - November 2015, Northern New Jersey

- Created spreadsheets and workflows to schedule, email, and measure the training performance of 120+ individuals. Achieved a 95.28% completion rating for eight formal trainings across a team of 107 employees.
- Researched and wrote trainings in partnership with leadership and fellow trainers from across the market. Collaborated with peers to generate engaging and rigorous trainings to introduce new practices.
- Established Mentor, Onboarding and Watch teams. Delegated responsibilities and empowered peers in order to foster an environment of inclusion. Motivated team members to provide a seamless training experience.

Expert, Apple Inc; — June 2012 - January 2015, Wayne, NJ

- Lead market team in individual sales numbers, NetPromoter score, and teamwork.
- Constructed new processes to solve customer concerns and provide a phenomenal checkout experience.
- Developed new channels of communication to create team cohesion.

Specialist, Apple Inc; — August 2008 - May 2012, Wayne, NJ

- Delivered workshops, assisted in recruitment of facilitators, and shared best practices with coworkers.
- Helped onboard 20+ employees and became a resource for knowledge and cultured.
- Provided transformational customer experiences and generated store-leading results.

Education

Rutgers University
Data Science
Bootcamp
2018

TableauDesktop I: Fundamentals
2017

Microsoft
Microsoft Excel for the
Data Analyst XSeries
2017

Rutgers University BA - Finance 2011

Github: https://github.com/smartsingh